That bore and I first met
when I was in community college.
He went to a fairly
prestigious college for our area.
At the time, my friends
were infatuated with him.
They called him broodingly sexy.
Going out with him
made me feel superior.
Then we had a child
Oh, so because it's three times
faster, the picture quality's…
Hey, Hayato.
How about a "Hi, Mom"?
Hi, Mom.
It's not that
my husband's a bad person.
He's not even a heavy drinker.
And while he doesn't bring home
a big paycheck,
he's a hard worker.
KOSAKU KAWAJIRI
SHINOBU
HAYATO
But…
I entered into marriage
with a complete stranger to love.
Hmph. So he's finally home.
All he ever says to me is,
"where's dinner,"
"make me a bath,"
and "I'm going to bed."
I'm married to a bore…
I'm home.
Where's dinner?
Oh, you're home?
I didn't even hear you come in.
I was too busy to cook,
so that's all there is.
But I got you your favorite.
RAMEN
LAND
I wonder if he's pissed…
If you've got the guts,
then show me what you got.
Who am I kidding?
You're gonna sit there stuffing your face
in silence like you always do.
Good evening!
This is Morioh Radio.
Kai Harada, here,
your neighborhood
- purveyor of good vibes.
- What are you doing?
And how is everyone
on this fine night?
Allow me to ease you
into a mellow evening…
EPISODE 25
HEART FATHER
Fifteen minutes by car
from Morioh Station…
MORIOH STATION
in an area known for
its views and villas, is his house.
YOSHIKAGE KIRA'S HOUSE
Or I should say, it was his house,
when he was still Yoshikage Kira.
KIRA
He now has a new face,
a new family, a new job,
a new place to call home.
I'm sure he'll never
turn up here again.
- There's not a dead body
- But we had no choice
- in the fridge, is there?
- but to search the place.
The only clues we're gonna
find to this new man's whereabouts,
are gonna be right here
in this house.
Is that his album?
Sure looks like him.
THIRD GRADE
SUMMER CAMP
7-25-1974
Yoshikage Kira…
Born in Morioh, January 30th, 1966.
He's 175 centimeters tall,
and weighs 65 kilograms.
Blood type is A.
He was born to older parents.
He was 21 when his father,
Yoshihiro, fell ill and died.
Seems his mother died
of old age soon after.
In 1988, he graduated with
a degree in literature from D College.
Same year, he became an employee of
Kameyu department store in S City.
In 1993, he transferred to
the Morioh branch.
He has no previous criminal record.
Never married. Has no close friends.
Has no lover.
Never had any surgery.
We have nothing to go by like fingerprints,
dental records, or surgical scars.
Not a single lead anywhere.
Look. These trophies and plaques…
HIGH SCHOOL MUSIC RECITAL
VIOLIN
3RD PLACE
YOSHIKAGE KIRA
They all say third place.
MIDDLE SCHOOL TRACK
200 METER HURDLES
3RD PLACE
YOSHIKAGE KIRA
He certainly wasn't
a star scholar-athlete.
AWARD
GRADE SCHOOL
WRITING CONTEST
OVERALL 3RD PLACE
Nothing speaks to his talents.
Was it sports? Music? Writing?
Even in this photo, he's doing
his best to not stand out.
He's never been the object
of ridicule or envy…
He reveals his strengths
and weaknesses to no one.
Which means…
It was clearly intentional.
He was concealing his extraordinary
talent and intellect.
He knew that was the best
way to stay out of trouble.
My hope in coming here
was to uncover his hobbies,
special interests, anything…
Hobbies? Well I found…
Seems he keeps a bunch
of jars in this drawer.
See?
Looks like a bunch
of bonito flakes.
And what are these numbers?
"1983" … Must be the year.
They kinda stink.
What do you think they are?
I think they're fingernail clippings.
Huh?
W-Whose nails
do you think they are?!
Th-They couldn't be…
No, they're his own.
They're not from his victims.
He kept meticulous notes.
Notes? You mean the numbers
on the jars?
So he's been collecting
these things since 1983?
For the past fifteen years?
THUMB | INDEX FINGER |
MIDDLE FINGER | RING FINGER | PINKY
[NAIL GROWTH
GREATER THAN 30 cm, BY YEAR]
RIGHT HAND
Gah! Every finger! The detail!
So in 1983, his right thumb…
grew a nail that was
31.5 centimeters long?
1983 was the year
he murdered Reimi Sugimoto.
The records begin
in that year.
He reached an age
where he could no longer
repress his murderous impulses.
Whoa! The next page he's got
all the info on his toenails!
Looks like
our unremarkable office worker
has a rather remarkable hobby.
NAIL GROWTH
GREATER THAN 30 cm, BY YEAR
KEEP UP THE GOOD WORK!!
NO ONE CAN STOP YOU.
It's a form of divination.
It's said Jewish merchants
observed sunspots
to predict their economic prospects.
Yoshikage Kira seems to
be tying his nail growth
to his physical and
mental preparedness…
His preparedness,
of course, to kill.
1999!
By June of this year,
they'd already grown to
over 20 centimeters!
He's crazy. He's sick!
But this won't help us
track him down.
There might be something else.
Does this mean someone
else is in this house?
Definitely seems that way.
Josuke, be prepared.
Think he's got
a partner in crime?
No… Not a chance.
More people means more risk
for being caught.
A partner could rat him out.
There's nothing
he would mistrust more.
This is…
Mr. Jotaro, I'd like you
to take a look at that camera.
I-It's his father… Kira's father!
He's in the picture,
right behind us!
But…
Shit. We're in a shit load
of trouble.
Does that mean he's a ghost?
Yeah. Considering Reimi Sugimoto,
it's possible his father is stuck
in a kind of spiritual limbo
between the land of
the living and the dead.
Look at his expression.
Looks like he wants us
to make a quick exit.
NUMBER WITHHELD
PUBLIC
Are you trying to scare us
with your ghost energy?
Something's starting to make it
really difficult for us to leave.
Get the lead out and
pick up the phone, slacker!
I'm making it ring!
You think that face
is telling you to leave?
You're totally off, you moron!
It's the face of a man who will
never let you leave this house!
Go after my son,
and I'll make sure you die.
Dirty bastard! You know all about
the crimes your son has committed?
Hey, something wrong?
What's with all the noise?
Where are you?
Show yourself,
you geriatric ghost!
Ghost?!
Josuke, he's not hiding.
Huh?
Looks like Kira's father
has been here with us all along.
Look.
BOOM
Wha…? When did he…?
He's moving around
in the picture.
He called us from inside
the picture.
He threw the phone at you
from this picture, too.
I'll kill you…
Go after my dear son,
and I'll murder you!
Josuke!
We can attack ghosts
with our Stands!
Rohan-sensei used Heaven's Door
to read Reimi's memories!
Bastard!
Now what, creepy dick!
What?!
D-Damn!
Damage inflicted on
the photograph backfires to us!
Fix it now, Josuke!
We'll be scattered to pieces!
Josuke! Mr. Jotaro!
Those abilities…
Now I see!
You two have
special powers like my son!
Okuyasu, it's your turn now!
Use The Hand to cut
that old man out of the picture!
Gotcha! You put the job
in the right hands, Josuke!
Huh?
O-Okuyasu?
W-What the—?!
How did I run straight
into the window?
M-My hands are coming out
all the way over there!
Something's keeping me
from entering the room!
That's…
A-A wall!
There's some kind of
invisible wall right here!
I can't break it! No!
Finally figured it out, eh?
That's the edge of the photo!
You may think you're in the room,
but you're not.
I'm a ghost living in a photograph…
I can control the space of
any photograph in which I appear.
With that camera,
I can confine a person's spiritual
energy within a photograph!
That's my special little trick!
That room is inside the picture!
If you damage the photo,
you damage the spiritual energy too,
effectively causing
grave harm to yourselves!
We're inside the picture?
I'm looking right at it!
You're clearly a bit on
the dim side,
so let me spell it out for you.
After I kill those two,
I'll ensnare the both of you
and shred you to pieces!
J-Josuke! Jotaro!
I'll kill you…
You bastard! Stop, damn it!
Jotaro, what are you doing?
Do something with your super
strong Star Platinum!
Josuke… I've thrown in the towel.
Huh?
Stopping that old-timer's attacks
is downright impossible.
If every bit of damage we deal him
comes right back to us,
then stopping time with
Star Platinum is useless.
If it's pointless, I don't bother.
I can't believe what
I'm hearing, Mr. Jotaro.
What the fudge are you saying?!
I'll kill you!
Your heads got some good spin!
H-He's got a knife…
What?!
I can't touch it! Mr. Jotaro!
I've given up on
stopping the geezer.
But…
Wha—?
If he really controls
any photograph he's in…
then maybe all we have to do
is take a picture of him by himself,
so he's alone.
What?!
You managed to sidestep
my attack… Blast it!
Josuke, leave 'em with
some words of wisdom.
Stick 'em with
a little style!
Y-You weren't so scary after all,
you big dumb idiot!
THE HAND
Damn you!
So you're seasoned fighters
I see.
You have battled foes
like my son
over and over again,
haven't you!
The dick can get out,
cause he's a ghost, remember…
We need to make sure you
stay put and behave yourself.
There's something in this house
you really don't want us to find.
That's why you attacked us.
I get it.
So if you fold him in half,
there's no way he can get out.
He can't run away.
Okuyasu and Koichi,
you've got this room.
We'll search the right side.
I can't protect
my son like this! Damn it!
If it falls into their hands…
But what in the world is it
do you think
that he doesn't want us to find?
I'm not sweating it.
If Kira's old man there turns white
as a ghost, then we should be good.
I-I can't breathe…
I-It's torture…
Please, just a little.
Just poke some holes
in the tape and let me breathe…
Y-You really can't breathe?
Hey, Koichi,
he's pulling your leg.
He wants you to make
an opening so he can escape.
I know you don't believe me,
b-but I'm really dying in here!
Well, I am claustrophobic,
so I guess I do sorta
get how he feels…
Oh, quit bitching. So you really
want a breathing hole, eh?
Fine. I'll give you
some breathing holes…
With a bunch of tacks.
W-What are you doing?!
Damn it! Get me out of here,
you wretched little punk!
There he is.
Those tacks aren't
going anywhere.
Tacks? I'm blind as a bat,
but if my guess is right,
they stuck me to the post.
Which gives me a great idea!
You don't realize it, but those tacks
are my ticket out of here!
And it couldn't be simpler!
Much obliged!
So long, suckers!
Wha…?!
Hey, you bastard…
What was that sound?
What did you do?
Say something, damn it!
O-Okuyasu, now we're really in a mess!
I think he just ran away!
Jotaro! H-He broke loose!
I-It's my fault. I stuck some
tacks in it, and then he did something!
You've been duped, dummy!
I just psyched you out and won.
What?!
Th-This is…
What's this doing here?
It can't be!
It's the bow and arrow…
But we already got them…
I thought the Speedwagon Foundation
was keeping them safe and sound…
There's another set?
Josuke, watch out!
Kira's father escaped!
What?!
With this very arrow,
Yoshikage's Deadly Queen was born!
The real game-changer
is the arrow!
I'll never surrender the arrow!
R-Reverb, Koichi!
Sick Act 1 on him!
I can't, he's too far away!
I can't believe this…
So what Kira's father didn't want us
to find was the bow and arrow!
D-Damn it!
It's all my fault!
No, Okuyasu.
He was the superior opponent.
There's no mistaking Kira is his son.
It's their unrelenting tenacity
to survive at all costs that
got the best of us.
As long as they don't get
this arrow, we'll be fine.
This little beauty will
make even more enemies for them!
The bow and arrow, huh…
I see.
I thought there might
be more than one set.
That explains how
DIO and his henchmen
were able to pull together such
a large group of Stand users so quickly.
With multiple sets of
bows and arrows,
they built an army of minions
across the globe.
Kira's father probably
obtained this set from Enyaba the witch,
and eventually,
Okuyasu's brother, Keicho,
got a hold of one, too,
before arriving in this town.
Stand users really do seem
to be drawn to each other.
Yoshikage, where are you?
Even as a little boy,
you couldn't repress
your urges to kill women.
But if that's what makes you happy,
I'll support and protect you.
You are…
my one and only son.
KOSAKU KAWAJIRI
SHINOBU
HAYATO
What's with the change of heart?
You're actually cooking?
How is that even possible…
Two plates? This one's for me?
You want me to eat
something you cooked?
Are you insane?
Hey! Cut your nails later!
Didn't you just cut them
last night?
They sure grow fast…
Oh… It actually tastes amazing…
HEART FATHER
A little kitty cat!
What's wrong?
Were you crying all night
at the top of that tree
because you couldn't get in?
Hey! You closed that damn
window near the tree, didn't you?!
I've told you over and over
not to shut it!
What's wrong, kitty?
Why are you so worked up?
Cats hate water.
My apologies. I wasn't thinking.
I won't do it again.
Something's strange.
Something strange is going on with him.
He suddenly starts cooking
for me,
and now, he's using an actual blade
instead of his electric razor.
Blades always give him razor burn…
Hey, you still haven't paid
last month's rent.
Including this month,
you now owe me 260,000 yen.
Pay up right now!
Rent?
You heard him.
Go get the money from the safe.
The safe?
Hurry! You're the only one who
knows the combination to the safe!
Hey, what are you…
Thank you for coming
so early in the morning, sir.
But I seem to be a bit
short on cash right now.
Huh?
I'm not playing around!
I should've known
you wouldn't be able to afford
my gorgeous home with
that pathetic salary, you schmuck!
Learn to live within your means!
- Right away—
- No, I think you misunderstood.
When I said
I was a bit short, look.
I meant that I had only
a little over 500,000 yen.
I'll only be able to pay
for this month,
last month, and the next
two months in advance.
Will that suffice?
Well, yes I…
Thank you very much.
Until next time!
Y-You…
You must have stolen that
money from the landlord.
I don't know how you did it,
but you stole it from his bag,
didn't you?
Most people in this situation…
would be filled with
fear and disgust…
But his gusto…
The way he stole the money…
This person,
after so many years together,
for the first time, he makes me…
He's awakened in me
pangs of romantic passion…
EPISODE 26
ROSHAM BOY IS HERE!